[
	{
		"id": "java-1",
		"question": "What does this code segment print? <div class=\"code\">static void increment(int index) { <br> &ensp;index++; <br>} <br> <br>public static void main(String[] args){ <br>  &ensp;int i = 0; <br>  &ensp;increment(i); <br> &ensp;i++; <br>  &ensp;System.out.println(i); <br>}</div>",
		"correct_answer": "1",
		"incorrect_answers": [
			"3",
			"0",
			"2"
		]
	},
	{
		"id": "java-2",
		"question": "What class can use a method from another class without a visibility modifier?",
		"correct_answer": "Any class from the same package",
		"incorrect_answers": [
			"Any class",
			"Any class that extends this class",
			"Any class from any subpackage of this package"
		]
	},
	{
		"id": "java-3",
		"question": "What is an unchecked exception?",
		"correct_answer": "An exception that extends RuntimeException of Error that you do not need to catch or rethrow",
		"incorrect_answers": [
			"An exception that extends RuntimeException that you may catch but cannot rethrow",
			"An exception that can be of any type, and that you do not need to catch or rethrow",
			"An exception that extends RuntimeException that you cannot catch but can rethrow"
		],
		"fr": "https://blog.octo.com/la-gestion-des-exceptions-en-java/"
	},
	{
		"id": "java-4",
		"question": "How can you add a method to an existing interface without having to modify the classes that already implement it?",
		"correct_answer": "You make this method a default method",
		"incorrect_answers": [
			"You provide an implementation of this method in a separate static class",
			"You make this method an abstract class",
			"You cannot add a method to an interface without implementing in the existing implementing classes"
		]
	},
	{
		"id": "java-5",
		"question": "What does a class need to do when it declares that it is implementing an interface?",
		"correct_answer": "It must be declared as abstract OR implement each of the interface's abstract methods, apart from the methods of the Object class.",
		"incorrect_answers": [
			"It must implement each of the interface's abstract methods and override the default methods",
			"It must be declared as abstract",
			"It must implement each of the interface's abstract methods"
		]
	},
	{
		"id": "java-6",
		"question": "What will be the output of the following program? <div class=\"code\"><p>public class MyFirst {</p><p>&nbsp; &nbsp;public static void main(String[] args) {</p><p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; MyFirst obj =newMyFirst(n);</p><p>&nbsp; &nbsp;}</p><p><br></p><p>&nbsp; &nbsp;static int a = 10;</p><p>&nbsp; &nbsp;static int n;</p><p>&nbsp; &nbsp;int b = 5;</p><p>&nbsp; &nbsp;int c;</p><p><br></p><p>&nbsp; &nbsp;public MyFirst(int m) {</p><p>&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp; System.out.println(a + &quot;, &quot; + b + &quot;, &quot; + c + &quot;, &quot; + n + &quot;, &quot;+m);</p><p>&nbsp; &nbsp;}</p><p><br></p><p>&nbsp; &nbsp;// Instance Block</p><p>&nbsp; &nbsp;{</p><p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; b= 30;</p><p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; n = 20;</p><p>&nbsp; &nbsp;}</p><p>&nbsp; &nbsp;// Static Block</p><p>&nbsp; &nbsp;static {</p><p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; a = 60;</p><p>&nbsp; &nbsp;}</p><p>}</p></div>",
		"correct_answer": " 60, 30, 0, 20, 0",
		"incorrect_answers": [
			"10, 5, 0, 20, 0",
			"10, 30, 20",
			"60, 5, 0, 20"
		],
		"source": "https://www.javatpoint.com/"
	},
	{
		"id": "java-7",
		"question": "Which of the following option leads to the portability and security of Java?",
		"correct_answer": "Bytecode is executed by JVM",
		"incorrect_answers": [
			"The applet makes the Java code secure and portable",
			"Use of exception handling",
			"Dynamic binding between objects"
		],
		"source": "https://www.javatpoint.com/"
	},
	{
		"id": "java-8",
		"question": "What is the return type of the hashCode() method in the Object class?",
		"correct_answer": "int",
		"incorrect_answers": [
			"Object",
			"long",
			"void"
		],
		"source": "https://www.javatpoint.com/"
	},
	{
		"id": "java-9",
		"question": "What does the expression float a = 35 / 0 return?",
		"correct_answer": "Infinity",
		"incorrect_answers": [
			"0",
			"Not a Number",
			"Run time exception"
		],
		"source": "https://www.javatpoint.com/"
	},
	{
		"id": "java-10",
		"question": " Evaluate the following Java expression, if x=3, y=5, and z=10: <div class=\"code\">++z + y - y + z + x++ </div>",
		"correct_answer": "25",
		"incorrect_answers": [
			"20",
			"23",
			"24"
		],
		"source": "https://www.javatpoint.com/"
	},
	{
		"id": "java-11",
		"question": "What will be the output of the following program? <div class=\"code\"><p>public class Test { &nbsp;</p><p>public static void main(String[] args) { &nbsp;</p><p>&nbsp; &nbsp; int count = 1; &nbsp;</p><p>&nbsp; &nbsp; while (count &lt;= 15) { &nbsp;</p><p>&nbsp; &nbsp; System.out.println(count % 2 == 1 ?&quot;***&quot;: &quot;+++++&quot;); &nbsp;</p><p>&nbsp; &nbsp; ++count; &nbsp;</p><p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; }</p><p>&nbsp; &nbsp; }</p><p>&nbsp;} &nbsp;</p></div>",
		"correct_answer": "8 times *** and 7 times +++++",
		"incorrect_answers": [
			"15 times ***",
			"15 times +++++",
			"Both will print only once"
		],
		"source": "https://www.javatpoint.com/"
	},
	{
		"id": "java-12",
		"question": "Which of the following for loop declaration is not valid?",
		"correct_answer": "<div class=\"codeAnswer\">for ( int i = 99; i >= 0; i / 9 )</div>",
		"incorrect_answers": [
			"<div class=\"codeAnswer\">for ( int i = 7; i <= 77; i += 7 )</div>",
			"<div class=\"codeAnswer\">for ( int i = 20; i >= 2; - -i )</div>",
			"<div class=\"codeAnswer\">for ( int i = 2; i <= 20; i = 2* i )</div>"
		],
		"source": "https://www.javatpoint.com/"
	},
	{
		"id": "java-13",
		"question": "Which of the following is true about the anonymous inner class?",
		"correct_answer": "It has no class name",
		"incorrect_answers": [
			"It has only methods",
			"Objects can't be created",
			"It has a fixed class name"
		],
		"source": "https://www.javatpoint.com/"
	},
	{
		"id": "java-14",
		"question": "Which option is false about the final keyword?",
		"correct_answer": "A final class cannot extend other classes.",
		"incorrect_answers": [
			"A final method cannot be overridden in its subclasses.",
			"A final class cannot be extended.",
			"A final method can be inherited."
		],
		"source": "https://www.javatpoint.com/"
	},
	{
		"id": "java-15",
		"question": "Given that Student is a class, how many reference variables and objects are created by the following code? <div class=\"code\"><p>Student studentName, studentId;</p><p>studentName = new Student();</p><p>Student stud_class = new Student();</p></div>",
		"correct_answer": "Three reference variables and two objects are created.",
		"incorrect_answers": [
			"Two reference variables and two objects are created.",
			"One reference variable and two objects are created.",
			"Three reference variables and three objects are created."
		],
		"source": "https://www.javatpoint.com/"
	},
	{
		"id": "java-16",
		"question": "Which of the following is a valid syntax to synchronize the HashMap?",
		"correct_answer": "<div class=\"codeAnswer\">Map m1 = Collections.synchronizedMap(hashMap); </div>",
		"incorrect_answers": [
			"<div class=\"codeAnswer\"> Map m = hashMap.synchronizeMap();</div>",
			"<div class=\"codeAnswer\"> HashMap map =hashMap.synchronizeMap();</div>",
			"<div class=\"codeAnswer\"> Map m2 = Collection.synchronizeMap(hashMap);</div>"
		],
		"source": "https://www.javatpoint.com/"
	},
	{
		"id": "java-17",
		"question": "<p>Given that strings is an ArrayList with the following elements: &quot;one&quot;, &quot;two&quot; and &quot;three&quot;, what does the following code do?</p><div class=\"code\"><p>for (string s : strings){</p><p><span>&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;</span>System.out.println(&quot;s = &quot; + s);</p><p><span>&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;</span>strings.remove(&quot;two&quot;);</p><p>}</p></div>",
		"correct_answer": "The code throws a ConcurrentModificationException",
		"incorrect_answers": [
			"The code throws a ArrayOutModificationException",
			"The code prints \"one\" and then \"three\"",
			"The code throws an IllegalStateException"
		],
		"source": ""
	},
	{
		"id": "java-18",
		"question": "<p>You have the following code</p><div class=\"code\"><p>try (Reader reader1 = new FileReader(&quot;log.txt&quot;);</p><p>&nbsp; Reader reader2 = new FileReader(&quot;log.txt&quot;)){</p><p>&nbsp; // some code</p><p>} catch (IOException e){</p><p>}</p></div><p>At run time, the constructor of reader2 throws an IOException, and the close() method of reader1 also throws an IOException. What exception(s) is/are caught in this code ?</p>",
		"correct_answer": "The exception thrown by the construction of reader2",
		"incorrect_answers": [
			"The exception thrown by the closing of reader1",
			"A third exception is caught, wrapping the two first exceptions",
			"Both exceptions are caught"
		],
		"source": ""
	},
	{
		"id": "java-19",
		"question": "You need to concatenate a list of instances of String together. What precautions should you take ?",
		"correct_answer": "Avoid the unnecessary creation of instances of String",
		"incorrect_answers": [
			"Properly flush the buffer of string in the returned String",
			"Properly flush the buffer of strings",
			"Make sure all the elements of the list are properly consumed"
		],
		"source": ""
	},
	{
		"id": "java-20",
		"question": "You need to distribute your application as a JAR file on the internet. How can you make your customer sure that the JAR they will download has not been modified by anyone?",
		"correct_answer": "You can sign it so that the JVM can check for its integrity",
		"incorrect_answers": [
			"You can distribute a password along with it",
			"You can distribute a hash code along with it",
			"You can hash each class in it"
		],
		"source": ""
	},
	{
		"id": "java-21",
		"question": "What will be the output of the following program? <div class=\"code\"><p>public class MyFirst {</p><p><span>&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;</span>public static void main(String[] args) {</p><p><span>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;</span>System.out.println(&quot;main&quot;);</p><p><span>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;</span>MyFirst obj = new MyFirst(n);</p><p><span>&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;</span>}</p><p><span>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</span>public MyFirst(int m) {</p><p><span>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;</span>System.out.println(&quot;constructor&quot;);</p><p><span>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</span>}</p><p><span>&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;</span>{</p><p><span>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</span>System.out.println(&quot;instance&quot;);</p><p><span>&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;</span>}</p><p><span>&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;</span>static {</p><p><span>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</span>System.out.println(&quot;static&quot;);</p><p><span>&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;</span>}</p><p>}</p></div>",
		"correct_answer": "static -> main -> instance -> constructor",
		"incorrect_answers": [
			"main -> constructor -> static -> instance",
			"main -> static -> constructor -> instance",
			"static -> instance -> main -> constructor"
		],
		"source": "self"
	},
	{
		"id": "java-22",
		"question": "<p>The following code is a part of a Java program&nbsp;</p><div class=\"code\"><p>String a = &quot;Hello&quot;;</p><p>String b = &quot; World&quot;;</p><p>a.concat(b);</p></div><p>How many instances of <span class=\"codeInLine\">String</span> are created at the end of the program?</p>",
		"correct_answer": "3",
		"incorrect_answers": [
			"2",
			"4",
			"1"
		],
		"source": ""
	},
	{
		"id": "java-23",
		"question": "You need to call a method that throws <span class=\"codeInLine\">IOException</span> and <span class=\"codeInLine\">FileNotFoundException</span>. Knowing that <span class=\"codeInLine\">FileNotFoundException</span> is an extension of <span class=\"codeInLine\">IOException</span>, among the following catch clauses, which one is NOT correct?",
		"correct_answer": "<div class=\"codeAnswer\">catch(FileNotFoundException e){}catch(IOException e){}</div>",
		"incorrect_answers": [
			"<div class=\"codeAnswer\">catch(FileNotFoundException | IOException e){}</div>",
			"<div class=\"codeAnswer\">catch(Exception e){}</div>",
			"<div class=\"codeAnswer\">catch(IOException e){}</div>"
		],
		"source": ""
	},
	{
		"id": "java-24",
		"question": "The maximum value you can store in an int is 2147483647. What does the following code print out? <div class=\"code\"><p>public static void main(String[] args){</p><p>&nbsp; int max = 2147483647;</p><p>&nbsp;System.out.println(max+1);</p><p>}</p></div>",
		"correct_answer": "-2147483648",
		"incorrect_answers": [
			"-1",
			"It throws an OperationOverflowException",
			"0"
		],
		"source": ""
	},
	{
		"id": "java-25",
		"question": "Which functional interface does not return a value?",
		"correct_answer": "Consumer",
		"incorrect_answers": [
			"Unary operator",
			"Supplier",
			"Predicate"
		],
		"source": ""
	},
	{
		"id": "java-26",
		"question": "Why are Java streams considered lazy?",
		"correct_answer": "Because intermediate operations are not evaluated until the terminal operation is invoked",
		"incorrect_answers": [
			"Because, when the terminal operation is called, traversal of streams begins and the associated function is performed one by one",
			"Because intermediate operations are evaluated before the terminal operation is invoked",
			"Because, when the intermediate operation is called, traversal of streams begins and the associated function is performed one by one"
		],
		"source": ""
	},
	{
		"id": "java-27",
		"question": "You have a stream of strings of characters. You want to concatenate all those strings using a comma as a separator. How do you proceed?",
		"correct_answer": "Collect the elements using the Collectors.joining() collector, passing the comma as a parameter.",
		"incorrect_answers": [
			"Collect the elements in a StringJoiner and call join() on that object, passing the comma as a parameter.",
			"Reduce the stream in a StringBuilder, using the StringBuilder::add as the reduction function.",
			"Collect the elements in a list and call join() on that list, passing the comma as a parameter."
		],
		"source": ""
	},
	{
		"id": "java-28",
		"question": "What does it mean for a field to be final?",
		"correct_answer": "Its value must be set during the construction of the object and cannot be modified.",
		"incorrect_answers": [
			"The field cannot be overridden in any extension this class may have.",
			"Once set, its value can only be modified within the instance initializer block.",
			"The field is a constant, accessible from all the class instances."
		],
		"source": ""
	}
]